AUSTIN O'NEIL

iOS Developer





📞 (303) 335-5761 🖂 austin@tangentsyste.ms 🏻 austinoneil.me 🔘 guitarguy199 in austinroneil







PERSONAL SUMMARY

A self-driven iOS Developer with 3+ years of development experience, and a combined 10+ years of customer service, sales, and business consulting experience. Seeking a small-tomedium-sized business in need of new functionality, debugging, and/or scaling their iOS platform.

LANGUAGES

Swift Objective-C HTML CSS Javascript

TOOLS & FRAMEWORKS

UIKit, SwiftUI, CloudKit, MapKit, RealityKit, CoreML, CoreData, Realm, Firebase

Bootstrap, express.js, NodeJS

Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch

PAST EXPERIENCE

PAST EXPERIENCE CONT.

FOUNDER

Tangent Systems, 2015-Present

- At self-founded freelance consulting company, advise and assist clients by optimizing multiple facets of their businesses, including: web development, analytics, payroll, human resources, social media marketing, and training.
- Built a comprehensive e-commerce platform for a Denver-based clothing company. Created viral Twitter marketing campaign, leading to a 300% increase in sales. Assisted with order fulfillment, profit and loss, and website maintenance.
- Assist restaurants in opening stages by implementing training, marketing, and staffing programs. Assist with back-end point of sale setups. Work with suppliers and partners to smoothly implement new products.
- Communicate complex concepts to clients by condensing information into easily understandable presentations.

BARTENDER/SERVER

Bartender/Server, The Kitchen, Renaissance Hotel, TAG Restaurant Group - Denver, CO 2018-Present

- Demonstrate above-average communication skills with customers and staff. Provide four-star table service at critically-acclaimed restaurants, including Kimbal Musk's "The Kitchen Bistro" concept.
- Maintain an expert-level knowledge of dynamic and frequently rotating menus, including: sourcing, flavor profiles, and potential allergens.
- Assist as interim manager at TAG concept, Los Chingones, leading a team and performing back-end data entry. Bartend at the mixology level at Renaissance Hotel bar, with a focus on local spirits. Participated in monthly Battle of the Bartenders competitions.

ONLINE SALES AND LEASING CONSULTANT

Asbury Automotive Group, 2017-2018

- Consistent above-average sales volumes month-to-month, with average closing ratio 13.5% (+1.5% above company average). Assist customers with online purchase program to establish rapport and convert to sales.
- Obtained proficiency with in-house online tools, such as CRM and interdepartmental sales funnels at various dealerships, including sales, finance, accounting, titling/tags, and service.
- Consistently handle and successfully resolve customer feedback and complaints regarding each department to ensure enhanced reputation management.

TRAINING DIRECTOR

Chick-fil-A, Inc., 2012-2017

- Shift management and oversight of daily operations at a Chick-fil-A franchise which netted over \$3Million in sales annually and resulted in progressive leadership responsibilities.
- Customer interfacing, including complaint/concern resolution.
- Coordination with other Director teams, including marketing and catering.
- Oversaw all training for new employees. Designed and developed "growth template" to allow systemic advancement from cashier through Director.
- Award Received \$1,000 CFA scholarship, per recommendations from Owner/Operator and guests.

EDUCATION